all right I would like to welcome our
next speaker on stage uh Robertson
Taylor he works as Solutions engineer at
Marco and uh he will uh speak about um
vector embeddings and training high
quality models thanks and please welcome
Robertson thank you we're going to start
with a little bit of audience
participation so sorry on Zoom uh who's
enjoyed Hy stack so far easy question
all right now I see who's not going to
answer uh who has embedding models that
they're using in production for
retrieval who's using multimodal
embeddings who's fine-tuning those
embedding models
okay interesting always good to see um
for those of you who raised your hand
for using the embeddings in production
and didn't raise them for fine tuning I
hope that this talk will convince you
that maybe the pre-train model you're
using isn't correct uh that there are a
lot of considerations to go into it and
that um taking a look at how you can get
a continuously improving uh embedding
model pipeline into production is
actually really important to drive
results so let's take a look at the
embedding retrieval landscape uh it's a
taale as oldest time at least for the
last 3 years um people come in they look
at hugg and face leaderboards they
choose a model they're like great it has
wonderful mtab scores or it's Leading
The Benchmark for my domain specific
thing and they decide to run an
embedding model they have a vector
database um and all of the industry you
know effort seems to be going towards
making these uh pieces more performant
um but that doesn't give you higher
quality results just gives you
potentially bad results a lot faster and
the line goes down a little bit faster
that that's what you're getting um there
are lot of questions you should ask When
selecting this initial base model like
how was it trained uh what data is
actually in the training Set uh was it
trained for symetric retrieval or
asymmetric retrieval and really just
like where are you starting from and
where are you trying to go go and are
your goals aligned
um this probably looks familiar to all
of you who have models in production uh
probably started with a proof of concept
probably had an off-the-shelf model uh
probably had some configuration tweaked
it a bit uh added a small sample of data
and then decided uh cool the results
look good and what I'm guessing most of
you saw was that as you start adding
documents to the vector database those
PC results don't necessarily translate
into
production and you might tweak the
search settings a bit more you might
index all of your documents get into
some pre-prod environment and you might
have some ETL pipelines uh have to set
up some monitoring to make sure that
when it does go into production it
actually stays up uh you might give a
few Vibe check uh looks at the results
make sure everything's good and
hopefully run some of your existing IR
metrics against this pre-prod data set
and this is where a lot of people wind
up realizing that fine-tuning a model
becomes necessary and I mean a ton of
steps there you're basically building a
new mlops pipeline to get embedding
retrieval trained in into production and
I mean you're setting up probably ETL
probably stitching together different
things deciding which features are
relevant selecting a base model getting
the training infrastructure set up and
then constructing some offline evals and
iterating uh hopefully at that point we
can get to an AB test lock in the search
config and align on what we're actually
trying to drive and then measure in you
know a real world setting is this
actually working and then you get to m m
where you need uh business as usual
maintenance but then you also need to
figure out can we iterate and
continuously improve this model because
it's a new retriever uh you wouldn't
just put your elastic search instance
into production and not play around with
boosting or not play around with how the
queries are being
constructed and then you get to do other
work so we think that you know there's a
real garbage and garbage out problem
with a lot of customers that we talk to
and this a&n graph might look really
familiar um but the the the gist of what
I want to get out of this slide is there
are a number of nodes at the bottom
you're hoping that the nearest nodes are
actually right uh you get back some
results Set uh you might have a
different search model and a different
uh embedding model um you might train
these separately but what really matters
at the end of the day is for a given
search are the nearest neighbors
actually relevant and how do we actually
get the correct you know distance
between items that should be collocated
and the queries that represent them uh
and well you'll see is a lot of training
regimes don't actually uh have this
explicitly encoded uh it's a very
incidental relationship so if you take a
look at this standard clip training we
have this buy encoder that everyone's
talking about a standard two Tower model
where we have texts that represents an
image we have an image we break it down
into patches and uh the the end result
is that we should minimize or we should
maximize the diagonal and try and
minimize all the off diagonal results
and hopefully what we get is when we
present these items in some sort of
space that pepper the a pup is the
closest item to the the actual image um
this doesn't really sound like retrieval
though because it's not it's this
incidental relationship where the text
is close to the image but does this
generalize to a query like if I said uh
cute dog on the grass uh there's no real
encoding of that into the training
regime we just have these images in the
alt text and if you're domain is really
well represented in that training data
maybe you're on like a stock photos
website where the the training process
is seen a lot of your data and and has a
good idea of the relationship between
the alt text that represents the image
or like the stock photo description and
the image then it might be great off the
shelf but um you can do
better and you can do better for a lot
of reasons so we have these binary
relationships that are trained with this
buy encoder process but there's no real
notion of rank so when I look for an SLR
camera uh from the clip training I can
get back an image um this relationship
is is pretty decent but I I don't have
any understanding of the magnitude of
that relationship so if I uh want to
represent a full product I might have
many different constituent Parts like
the metadata that represents it might
have categorical data might have a
description I might have multiple images
and um the model hasn't been trained in
a way to get this single Vector fused
representation and you need to first of
all be able to represent the items with
all of their constituent Parts but then
you need to understand you know the
magnitude of the relationship so if a
camera is purchased 1,300 times it's a
much better result than a camera that's
purchase five and that's really domain
specific if I run a budget camera shop
the items that I get back should be very
different than if I'm running uh a sort
of high-end uh camera store
and it's an interesting problem if you
want to experiment with it we do have a
data set it has about 10 million rows of
data um it's split down in the into
queries as well as about 100 products
per query it contains ranking
information it also has about 5 million
Unique Products so if you want to take a
stab at doing better than we're doing
with our regime that we'll talk about in
a few minutes uh please feel free to
give it a go um it's all open source
along with the uh training approach that
we used
and we just kind of get to this PO we
get to this point of wondering if
embeddings can actually incorporate Rank
and what that looks like so um for
simple use cases like a a rag
application where there is a true
onetoone relationship between an
information need and the document that I
should get back like what is the atomic
weight of gold has an answer um maybe
you don't need this rank but for one to
many relationships like you see in the
real world especially in things like
e-commerce umen sweater is a very
ambiguous query uh we need to have some
way to discriminate between the results
that we get back and return the ones
that are relevant and what that means in
the embedding space is we need to be
able to encode the similarity as part of
the angular relationship between the
items so we made a way to do that uh
there's an archive paper there will be a
QR code at the end don't feel the need
to uh stress out about typing it um but
the way that we've approached this is by
deconstructing the problem into a
left-and side where we have um you know
what could be your query and here it's
one part this could be many parts uh you
could for instance have a full product
representation and the left- hand side
that's the query uh to do personalized
search um and we have a right- hand side
that represents the objects that we're
trying to retrieve and in this case we
have a cat it has a title it has a
description and we need to have a
training regime that actually allows you
to um get this inter modality
relationship as well as the
intermodality relationship so from an
intermodality relationship perspective
we have a text encoder that takes in the
metadata representing an object as well
as the left hand side in this case the
query and um we see that we have this
Matrix over here that's very similar to
The Matrix you saw on the clip embedding
side but we also have this weighted
ground truth Matrix and the weighted
ground truth Matrix can be seen as kind
of like a collaborative filter except
the goal is to generalize so that when
we get an embedding out we understand
how to encode the ranking information
inside of it and this is learned
throughout the training process and um
the the idea is that we need a
generalizable way so that when we see a
new document when we see a new query
we're actually able to understand how it
should Rank and how it should perform
for a given query and what it's related
to and if we break it down this way we
actually get a ton of different use
cases for embeddings that aren't just
the standard sort of semantic search use
case so we do have that search we have
SLR camera we can use a business metric
uh that informs that weight to ground TR
M Matrix in this case at to carts and we
can say that this is the relevant
product metadata and it's all in a box
because this is a single Vector
representation so we train the fusion
into uh the
representation and we can handle
recommendations so we can preserve the
query to document relationship as well
as introduce a document to document
relationship things like entity
resolution and D duplication become
possible so uh you can see that the
Canon camera here is related to
full-frame mirrorless camera uh these
are likely duplicates so it has
applications to things like Marketplace
content uh conditional search this is
one that I think is actually really cool
and uh the idea is you can train a
subdomain behavior in the model so if
you have a USA Marketplace the ranking
of items might be different than any
Japanese Marketplace and by prefixing
and training that prefix into the model
uh we can actually get a conditional
search and personalization so that
single query plus document
representation uh returning an
individual lens uh classification uh we
can invert the relationship store the
actual tags for categories inside of the
vector database and then the query
becomes the documents that are coming in
um all of these are things that we have
done and interesting things that you can
do when you kind of deconstruct The Bu
encoder into a left hand side and the
right hand
side but you need data and there are a
lot of different types of data uh if
you're just starting out you might only
have access to external data like some
hugging face data sets some stuff on
GitHub uh potentially you have some
documents uh with the relevant metadata
maybe you wind up enriching them maybe
you use some of the llm assisted you
know augmentation of the records where
you you know say this is the category
for this or maybe you actually take the
document and do some sort of visual
reasoning over it and try and get some
queries uh out of the document um this
is okay like it's okay um what really
helps is getting actual production
search logs and getting actual relevance
judgments from your customers so based
on the actual business data that you
have who's added this to cart who's
interacted with this uh what's the dwell
time on a page after someone clicks on
this item you can start to really
understand uh how to make a domain
specific model uh but you have to do a
ton of stuff you have to clean you know
a ton of the standard stuff you see D
duplication and a multimodal use case
you also want to make sure that you have
no corrupted images you want to you know
kind of freeze the data set so you're
not using URLs or something where the
the data behind the URL might change um
filtering uh remove low intent
information so sticking with e-commerce
because that's where I spend a lot of my
time things like click-through rate can
be really weak signals and incorporating
them into your training can be really
noisy uh so sticking to a metric that's
either driving some sort of int Behavior
like a purchase or Discovery Behavior
like uh you know clicking through dwell
time um it's really useful and
augmentation also really powerful in the
multimodal use case that D duplication
use case you see becomes a lot easier
when you actually start to take in the
images and augment them because the
right match as an image is very similar
to an existing image so if you just
augment the image and train against this
augmented image to image pair uh you can
get a lot of this natural matching and
transformation image resizing get get
everything into cons a consistent shape
so that the the training process becomes
really streamlined and you know
splitting uh we're going to spend a lot
more time on creating eval splits later
but uh there's a lot of consideration
that goes into this that should go
beyond you know creating some sort of
2080 split and hoping model does
okay and what you get is a result set
here that looks something like this
where we can see the query cat we can
see that it has a ton of interactions uh
we can see for dog the same product ID
has no interactions it's probably a cat
collar and this should be trained into
the model um but there are a few things
to keep in mind when you're constructing
these result sets um namely uh
temporality is present in a lot of
domains so if you're running this
e-commerce store and it's Berlin in the
winter you probably want to get the
seasonality of the products baked into
the model uh where you know the results
in the fall might be different um and
you can use these outcomes as as
relevance judgments so you can really
start to use your user interactions as a
judge of relevance rather than relying
on some sort of human label data set and
often this comes with the benefit of
driving those metrics up so if you
choose to you know in the eval and
training process use the metrics that
you're actually looking to you know
improve then you have better
results oh and uh the last thing is if
you take into account these historical
search logs you get to avoid this kind
of cold start problem that people see
with offthe shelf embedding models so
you can train your existing good results
into the model uh maybe as part of the
filtering step you uh look at the
historical data and find items that will
have really high signal while getting
the benefit of uh you know this
embedding retrieval for results that
you're not particularly happy
with but which business metrics do we
choose so you kind of see there's a
conversion intent here and a discovery
intent here and this is one way to break
down this e-commerce use case where you
know a transaction super high conversion
intent kind of low Discovery intent um
also typically fewer of them uh at toart
is typically a really nice metric where
it shows that there's some amount of
Discovery that's desired but also some
amount of intent to actually complete a
purchase and you typically have way more
of those so when you're looking for
these relevance judgments depending on
the size of your data set you might have
to compromise a bit on if you're driving
a conversion intent metric going a bit
further on the Discovery intent side but
the goal should be if we're trying to
drive you know this this conversion that
we choose a metric that's further along
the conversion intent axis than the
discovery axis um but there are domains
where this isn't as true so if you're a
physical only retail store but you have
an online presence uh a lot of the
behavior that you want to drive is
actually Discovery based so we can look
at uh how people are actually going
through a website are they favoriting
things might be a good you know metric
to converge on um while things like
click through we still kind of remain a
bit
noisy all right eval splits um we see a
ton of people come to us with these sort
of 2080 sort of standard splits uh that
don't really track how well the model is
generalizing uh we tend to break down
the problem to four domains of novel
Corpus novel query zero shot and domain
and doing doing this allows you to kind
of figure out if the model is not
generalizing where's the problem uh
sometimes it's only on the query side
sometimes it's only on the Corpus side
uh and this becomes more important if
you do decide to start uh splitting out
your search model and your uh Corpus
model like we'll talk about in the
future um so being able to actually do
offline evals that take into account um
documents that you have seen uh and
queries that you have seen understand
you know the difference between those
result sets and how they perform in this
split really important uh but the
temporality uh is also something you you
should be keeping an eye on so we might
have training data we might know it's
good training data but keeping these uh
temporally relevant Windows of data
allows you to actually understand am I
doing well right now uh is there a need
to train a new search model is there a
need to reindex all the documents and uh
if you have the data volume it's always
really nice to be able to look at just a
temporally relevant window but if we
split these temporally relevant windows
in the same way then we can start to
subsample from them even with low data
so I can say I want to create a new
sample for evals and I want to split you
know 20% of the documents from an old
window but in the novel query bucket and
doing this make sure that you're not you
know skewing the the evaluation by uh
waiting unintentionally more towards one
of these quadrants
all right we've heard a lot about
matrioska representation learning over
the last two days um the idea I think at
this point is fairly simple uh we have a
base model in this case we'll talk about
a clip model and we can actually look at
truncating this down into smaller
dimensions and the real benefit here is
we are trading off the Storage uh for
you know uh we're we're trading off
storage for Speed and
relevance and we can go down to you know
really small dimensionality and and try
and find a good candidate set of results
uh but a lot of the times people aren't
actually looking at how this performs in
production and and baking this into
their evals so if you're going to do
something like mrl or you're going to do
something like
binarization uh the real thing that I
want to stress here is you should be
doing production aware training so we
talked about training GCL in a way where
we train for the fused representations
we train to learn how to combine the
individual documents but we need to be
aware of this when we're doing these
sort of storage optimizations as well
and the results uh results are on the
slide after this um but yeah there are a
ton of things generally applicable uh
you can adjust for your storage needs
after training uh great benefits but you
are actually sacrificing performance at
at lower dimensionalities and you're not
actually getting any sort of inference
uh benefits uh so one thing that we kind
of counsel people on is selecting a
model that has you know a dimensionality
that's appropriate uh partially because
uh a lot of the times these models have
a lower parameter count and it makes the
training process easier as
well but when we do train in a way
that's aware where uh that at inference
time there might be some sort of mrl
happening we see that the results become
much better um on the left hand side we
have a GCL train model uh the approach
we're talking about earlier in the talk
and on the right hand side we have an
mrl uh aware GCL trained model and we
can see that across sort of standard
search metrics the degradation and
quality uh becomes much lower when we
have trained in a way that lets the
model actually understand that we might
be doing mrl at inference so we can go
down even to 128 dimensions and see
really minimal ndcg gain or ndcg losses
um rrr err and rppp both have similar
results and overall this trend continues
into binarization as well
so binarization I'm a little bit more
skeptical of uh a lot of these storage
redu things I'm I'm a little bit more
skeptical of um there's a sort of Step
change that happens when you find tuna
model but when you're iterating on that
fine tune model the the gains might be a
bit more marginal so you might be
fighting for these sort of 3% increases
and quality and binarization and mrl can
kind of both eradicate those uh over
time so going into this being a little
bit skeptical but if you train the model
again to be aware that you might
binarize at INF time uh the degradation
becomes much lower to understand binary
quantization uh we take a vector it
might have different weights uh
associate or might have different values
at each point in the array for the
vector these are typically float 32s and
we turn those into uh one bit
representations um most of the time
sometimes people use negative values
they do a one negative one split with a
10h activation um this leads to a lot of
De generate queries actually or
degenerate degenerate representations
actually because if you think about the
hypersphere in this case just sphere
that these embeddings are on um there's
only n degrees of difference that are
possible with this one negative one
representation whereas if you think
about the uh one zero you actually have
n d or yeah n d dimensional hyperspheres
that are uh able to be represented so
you get two to a d degrees of difference
that you can represent with a one zero
model um but yeah so sigmoid activation
I think preferable to 10h activation um
but yeah you can you can reduce the
embedding space dramatically by doing
this binary quantization 32x uh space
Improvement
and the thing
to no I think I'm done with
that all right truncation aware training
here also uh you can see the results are
way more dramatic so we have this float
float uh on the left hand side uh it's
our Baseline uh mixed float
representation is all right but when we
go mixed binary uh you can see that the
the drop off here is about like
17% um we see the same sort of
degradation on ER and RVP and you're
really eradicating a lot of the benefit
so like unless you actually have
billions of vectors that you're trying
to store um I would ask myself is the
cost savings and storage savings
actually worth it
[Music]
um often I think not like especially
when you look on an Roi based basis like
how much you really saving by going down
to Binary um we typically see customers
decide that it's not not a
win all right so we have a few different
things that we can train in we can do
this rankle bear training we can do
smaller lower dimensionality
representation
uh we can do this
quantization um let's say we have a
model in production what does the
continuous Improvement pipeline look
like so let's say someone is on canva
they've searched for quote bubble
they've got them back four items that
all look reasonably
relevant um but users only interact with
two of them so we can start to aggregate
that data uh get our our judgment list
of what customers actually use and
aggregate per query and we can take a
temporal window of those queries using
the scores to influence the results and
we can do a four-way split of the
queries and scores and those buckets
that we talked about before we can do
our offline
evals and we can take a look and see if
there's been any sort of improvement
great this is if you're doing this
manually it's not super scalable and you
need to have a way to evaluate many
different candidates which means that
your offline eval actually has to be
pretty good so stick to the previously
discussed split uh use your standard
metrics um use your business metrics and
the evaluations um this is something
that for some reason people seem to
avoid um they seem to bucket things into
relevant or not relevant but missing out
in an item that has 1,300 ad to cards is
very different than missing out in an
item that has five and that should be
incorporated into your offline evals and
recency is great but we should use that
sub sampling approach that we talked
about earlier if there's not enough data
volume to actually get strong signal and
um seasonality of these sub samples is
also really important so like if you're
running an e-commerce store and you're
looking for you know jackets a jacket in
the winter might be different than a
jacket in the fall and if you subsample
across all these different buckets and
don't try to maintain some of the
seasonality uh influence then the
resulting models might not be great
and then finally you want to also
continuously improve on those offline
evals so measure the predictive power of
your offline evals how many times do
models that pass the offline evals or
show Improvement in offline evals
actually make it into production and
actually do well um it's really
important to make sure that you haven't
introduced some sort of uh degradation
in the offline eval
process and the naive way to go about
you know improving after this is cool we
have this let's say we put it in some
sort of repeatable pipeline we've
trained many different model candidates
uh we get a candidate model we deploy
the model we have to index a new
database we have to establish some sort
of routing for online AB evals uh we
have to do the actual online evals and
then we choose one great but this is way
more expensive and an embedding
retrieval use case than it is and you
know a sort of standard lexical
retrieval use case the the embedding
process is actually quite expensive and
if you're doing this reindexing for
every candidate model then you're going
to really slow down your rate of
progress um definitely better than
nothing uh but you you need to have some
sort of standard and flexible way to
train these candidate models or you can
even even get
here and after you get there uh maybe
you decide to do something a little bit
more clever like we had these candidate
models
uh we can sample from our existing
distribution so maybe we're trying to
improve head queries with this new model
um we can actually construct a query
cache so cache the query cach the
filters cache the facets uh figure out
what embeddings are actually retrieved
and then when that query comes in at
runtime we can return results from the
cache set and do an eval of if this new
cach set of embeddings is actually
potentially an improvement or at least
not like a severe degradation and doing
it way means that you can construct many
of these query caches and have many of
them running in parallel and evaluate
which of these candidate models might
actually be worth going to production uh
in like a way faster time
frame another thing that we see our
customers do is to uh search with a
different search embedding model and
embed the models with a basee embedding
model and the reason this works is
because the representation of the
embeddings or that the difference
between the items isn't actually
changing in a lot of data sets so like
if you have an e-commerce data set uh
the jackets that have clustered together
their their relationship to each other
is often not changing so if we freeze
the right hand side of the model
training process and just allow for a
new search model to be trained then we
can take advantage of evaluating a lot
of different search model candidates and
also incorporating seasonal Trends
without ever having to reindex the
vector database um a good example of
that would be like the query for iPhone
um iPhone today probably different than
iPhone in two years uh so when I search
for iPhone I want to get back the most
recent version um and I want to get the
most recent version of accessories but
we can get that behavior by just
changing the search Tower and changing
where the embedding for iPhone actually
points to at at search time and keep the
document representation the same um
where this doesn't work is in a domain
where the relationship between items
might actually uh be relevant uh so like
if I have a news story or let's take the
Olympics for example uh the the name of
the Turkish Sharpshooter probably should
be related to other Sharpshooters after
the Olympics and prior to the Olympics
that wasn't the case um so here we have
a case where the underlying
representation points to a different
place and the search query points to a
different place as well and if that's
the case this approach doesn't
necessarily work but typically because
it's a symmetric task we can actually uh
freeze just the right hand side and
train a new model for the search side um
some important notes Here uh the models
that you train to do this should start
from the document model checkpoint and
then you just take a temporal window uh
assuming you have enough data and then
you can get the those seasonal Trends
while also starting from the same place
uh from a document embedding checkpoint
standpoint
so I've said a lot of stuff about how we
train models but uh I'd be asking if the
approach actually works
um here we have the GS 10m Corpus that
we talked about before and you can see
that bm25 has about uh
07 oh I lost my labels here um I believe
this was ndcg yeah this is ndcg uh 07
ndcg pre-trained 0.1 ndcg GCL and domain
point6 and as far as generalization you
can see that for novel queries we do
quite well for novel Corpus we still do
quite well for zero shot uh just kind of
a slow curve down like you'd expect um
but you know we we have pretty REM
remarkable performance increases in each
category which makes sense when you
consider that Baseline bm25 doesn't have
any sort of ranking information and NRA
does the uh original pre-train clip
model and in production we kind of see a
similar Trend so here we have an example
of a customer with a GCL train model
they're using conditional embeddings uh
they're a Marketplace so in this case
they're SE uh segmenting things out by
Marketplace and instead of NCG here
we're just looking at cumulative gain
versus K where K is the number of items
retrieved and K1 you can see that the
pre-train model starts off pretty poor
and as we go up here this means that
we're returning more relevant results in
the first slot and you can kind of look
at the The Arc of the graph here as well
to see that uh the pre-train model it's
not like you go further out in the
result sets and start retrieving items
that actually could be relevant for the
ranker um and as we start iterating here
you can see that this curve goes further
and further up and starts plateauing
later which means that we're still
returning relevant results way further
out into the result set here and
um this is quite important because a lot
of people seem to think that they can
just solve a lot of the embedding rank
based problems with rankers uh but that
doesn't really matter if you're never
serving relevant results like if you're
never giving good candidates from the
vector retrieval to the ranker it's not
going to solve that problem and and this
is kind of what we've seen play out in
practice where people will put in a
pre-trained model and uh they'll get
back these huge result lists because
they're like hey maybe the first few
results aren't right maybe the rank's
not there but we can just return like
400 items and then the rerer is going to
solve the problem and the the way that
this plays out in practice especially
for customers with tens of millions or
hundreds of millions of items is uh just
returning 400 500 results isn't enough
um you need to be able to say that this
is a relevant item for our domain and
that's where we see people start to
really have uh performance benefits with
embedding
models I spoke really fast that was 45
minutes at my
hotel thank
you thank
you all right uh any questions from the
audience in the room to
Robertson hello thanks for the great
presentation thank you so let me ask you
when you you were comparing the ndcg
metrix yes this one so pretrain model
there is it's like a open source
pretrained model or is also a model fine
tuning your data no it's a open source
pre-trained model I think in this case
it was the clip lion Tob checkpoint uh
512 Dimension Mod so have you ended up
comparing like the your method with clip
tradition clip trained in your domain oh
trained in our domain yeah um I can get
you some benchmarks after the fact but
the the rank information becomes really
important okay thanks
yeah okay so there was a question from
um Sam online so he's asking uh any
recommendations on how to combine uh
different user signals into a combined
judgment score yeah um we have people
who do this with like functions of at
toart uh plus likelihood to convert on a
particular item and we don't really care
what the score is we just care that
there is some sort of objective score um
it does mean that you have to kind of
continuously train different models with
different score function candidates and
then you can evaluate based on actual
business metrics which one is
successful there was a question
here so my question is more related to
the machine learning side of the of the
training so uh usually in clip uh you
have to train with huge batch sizes and
I know uh by experience that um in
e-commerce you usually have lots of
class collisions when you train uh these
models so you you have multiple images
that look pretty much the same with very
similar uh descriptions so how did you
deal to
deal with those cases when you were
fine-tuning those models yeah um in this
case we had a really diverse set which
kind of helps with that problem um but
we have trained models for customers
with really like narrow domains like for
instance they might only have like shoes
that they sell and in that case limiting
the batch size but also having like
class labels of like what things are
related and trying to make it pseudo
random to avoid potential collisions can
can help
all right maybe vely related to this
question from Roman duk online how much
data have you collected from first
iteration to last iteration in this
customer example to get improved results
I don't know which one was this customer
example but maybe uh um I can give an
example um we've trained a model with a
large American Marketplace that had 1.5
billion rows of interaction data um
which is like three times the amount of
training data that was incorporated into
clip um it it works quite well uh you
can still incorporate a ton of items but
at really large data sizes I would take
a look at if you know reducing the
amount of data some temporarily relevant
subset of information makes
sense all right uh
Trey qu question one point in the talk
you mentioned that uh binarization of um
embeddings that with folks you've worked
with that they found it not worthwhile
yeah um however you know if you just do
like scalar quantization to like int8 or
something it's you know whatever
significant reduction in memory required
um versus relatively little recall
you've given up and if there's rescoring
or whatever like I'm just curious if you
could expound on why they determine it's
not worth it yeah um let me see if I can
go back to my my benchmarks there um in
our testing we've seen especially if we
incorporate more information into the
the embedding space like we want to
encode the rank as part of the angle um
that just going down to Binary
quantization loses a lot of that
information so we have we have less
ability to have these fine grained query
to document relationships that you can
train into the model um and we've seen
pretty significant drops and recall like
10 to to
177% uh after doing evaluations I don't
know if you've seen something different
be interested to take a look
you usually not within date when you get
further down um yes but um like like
binary quantization for sure I was
curious about other levels like oh dat
for example were saying inate and I was
right if you all the way to Binary you
obviously lose a lot of information um I
was curious about other levels yeah not
just like float 32 no ENT makes a lot
more sense um we we're typically working
with customers when we're doing this
sort of fine tuning process where like
very marginal changes and performance
have like really tangible Revenue impact
and like when you compare the cost of
losing some of that recall versus the
cost of storing the vectors in full size
uh we often find out it comes out to be
like a wash but if you have billions of
vectors like you're not working in some
sort of e-commerce store that might have
like probably Peak hundreds of millions
um maybe makes more
sense okay thank you one final question
from the online audience uh from deba
Mishra why performance in contrast of PA
learning was the model trained only in
binary labels relevant or irrelevant or
based on various subc categories like
product seasonality and other
combinations is that a question I think
so is it
question so I think the it's basically
two questions right so was it a binary
labels and then did you have some
segmentation on product seasonality say
yeah um so we can incorporate many
different pieces of metadata as long as
you give us relevance labels so sorry
I'm staring you down for this question
but uh as long as you give us some sort
of relevance judgment that's fine like
the the approach has been constructed to
kind to try and find some sort of noise
uh or signal from the noise of these
different constituent parts of metadata
um how much you weight those binary
relevance labels if they're incorporated
as part of the item metadata I don't
really know why they would be would no
that was question was just two questions
so one was binary or non-binary labels
yeah and then the other one was like the
segment segmentation like subcategories
oh um on the binary versus non-binary
labels um I would we often don't train
with negative pairs we we just train
with true positives um so if we just
erase the irrelevant results from the
training set we we typically find that
that works a bit better than like giving
them some sort of negative weight um but
a lot of that might be skewed by our
sort of domain niche of working mainly
in e-commerce where true negatives can
be hard to find okay I like I haven't
answered the question I'm
sorry all right thank you very much and
uh let's thank Robertson again